During his acceptance speech for the Nobel Peace Prize, Martin Luther King Jr. said, “I believe that unarmed truth and unconditional love will have the final word in reality.”
马丁·路德·金在诺贝尔和平奖的获奖演说中说：“我相信，手无寸铁的真理和无条件的爱，将在现实中拥有最终的决定权。”
More than five decades later, our society is still struggling to separate truth from fantasy, fact from fiction.
五十多年过去了，我们的社会仍难以把真相与幻想、事实与虚构区分开来。
From disputes over climate change to debates about how slavery is taught, America is at a crossroads.
从围绕气候变化的争论，到关于如何讲授奴隶制的辩论，美国正处在十字路口。
And the battle for equity is at the heart of these vital conversations.
而在这些至关重要的讨论中，争取公平的斗争处于核心位置。
Study after study shows that inequity has had appalling consequences.
一项又一项研究表明，不公已经造成了骇人的后果。
A 2020 report by Citi indicated that “Black students could have increased their lifetime incomes $90–$113 billion” if equity issues related to higher education had been adequately addressed over the past two decades.
花旗集团2020年的一份报告指出，如果过去二十年里与高等教育相关的公平问题得到充分解决，“黑人学生的终生收入本可以增加900亿至1130亿美元”。
This statistic represents a flood of issues we’ve failed to confront as a nation.
这一统计数据反映出大量问题，而我们这个国家一直未能正视这些问题。
It also highlights one truth: We’re missing out on valuable opportunities to bridge the differences that divide us.
它还凸显了一个事实：我们正在错失宝贵的机会，去弥合那些使我们彼此分裂的分歧。
However, by honoring King’s legacy, we can get our country back on the path toward true equity.
然而，通过弘扬马丁·路德·金的精神遗产，我们可以让国家重新走上通往真正公平的道路。
Students—and adults for that matter—simply cannot understand the conflicts we have today without understanding what caused them in the first place.
学生——其实成年人也一样——如果不了解我们今天面临的种种冲突最初因何而起，就根本无法理解这些冲突。
That means we have a responsibility to help them make connections between US history and current events.
这意味着，我们有责任帮助他们把美国历史与时事联系起来。
It also means giving them the tools they need to address inequity and bias in their own lives.
这也意味着，要为他们提供所需的工具，用来应对他们自己生活中的不公和偏见。
Adherence to these principles, along with a commitment to truthful dialogue, can help every student better appreciate how far we’ve come and more clearly see the roads we have yet to travel.
恪守这些原则，再加上坚持坦诚的对话，能帮助每个学生更好地认识到我们已经走了多远，并更清楚地看到我们还有哪些路要走。
With more truthful analysis of the need for more qualified, diverse educators, we can improve our recruiting, training, and retention strategies for schools across the country.
我们需要更多合格且多元化的教育工作者，如果能对这一需求作出更实事求是的分析，就能改进全国各地学校的招聘、培训和留任策略。
Unfortunately, our deeply rooted divisions are delaying these advancements.
遗憾的是，我们之间根深蒂固的分裂正在延缓这些进步。
A recent survey found that 77 percent of Americans believe the nation is “more divided than ever before”.
最近的一项调查发现，77%的美国人认为，这个国家“比以往任何时候都更加分裂”。
But reports of increased polarization shouldn’t persuade us to look away from one another.
但有关两极分化加剧的报道，不应让我们对彼此视而不见。
Instead, they should compel us to address our shared issues head-on.
相反，这些报道应当促使我们正面应对共同面临的问题。
We are not, as some would suggest, living in a “post-racial society”.
我们并不像有些人所说的那样，生活在“后种族社会”中。
We simply cannot afford to keep our heads buried in the sand when it comes to racial inequity.
在种族不公问题上，我们根本不能再把头埋在沙子里。
Unless we get honest about intolerance, bias, and how these social diseases impact the ways we treat one another, injustice will continue to haunt us.
除非我们坦诚面对不宽容、偏见，以及这些社会弊病如何影响我们相互对待的方式，否则不公不义将继续困扰我们。
But our children and our grandchildren deserve better.
但我们的子女和孙辈理应享有更好的境遇。
On this Martin Luther King Day and beyond, let’s commit to working together to disrupt the status quo.
在这个马丁·路德·金纪念日以及往后的日子里，让我们致力于携手合作，打破现状。
Let’s continue to build a better, more inclusive nation—in the words of Martin Luther King Jr., “a society at peace with itself, a society that can live with its conscience.”
让我们继续建设一个更美好、更包容的国家——用马丁·路德·金的话来说，就是“一个与自身和平相处的社会，一个能够问心无愧的社会”。